{
	"name": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice",
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": "When introduced into the body, ricin causes:\n\nA. pulmonary edema and circulatory failure.\nB. enlarged lymph nodes and extreme pain.\nC. necrosis of muscle tissue and cell destruction.\nD. intestinal obstruction and severe sepsis.\nSee Biologic Agents",
			"back": "pulmonary edema and circulatory failure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": "The process performed to artificially maximize the target population’s exposure to a biologic agent, thereby exposing the greatest number of people and achieving the desired result, is called:\n\nA. potentiation.\nB. weaponization.\nC. alkalization.\nD. dissemination.\nSee Weapons of Mass Destruction",
			"back": "weaponization."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": "Which of the following agents blocks the body’s ability to use oxygen and possesses an odor similar to almonds?\n\nA. Hydrogen cyanide\nB. Phosgene oxime\nC. Carbon monoxide\nD. Organophosphates\nSee Chemical Agents",
			"back": "Hydrogen cyanide"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": "Which of the following statements regarding anthrax is correct?\n\nA. Cutaneous anthrax has a 90% mortality rate.\nB. Anthrax is a deadly virus that replicates.\nC. Pulmonary anthrax is the deadliest form.\nD. There is presently no vaccine against anthrax.\nSee Biologic Agents",
			"back": "Pulmonary anthrax is the deadliest form."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": "Most terrorist attacks are:\n\nA. unplanned.\nB. nuclear attacks.\nC. impulsive.\nD. covert.\nSee EMT Response to Terrorism",
			"back": "covert."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": "The least harmful form of ionizing radiation is:\n\nA. neutron.\nB. beta.\nC. gamma.\nD. alpha.\nSee Radiologic/Nuclear Devices",
			"back": "alpha."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": "The chemical attacks that occurred in Tokyo between 1994 and 1995 were carried out by a(n):\n\nA. violent religious group.\nB. single-issue terrorist group.\nC. extremist political group.\nD. group of domestic terrorists.\nSee What Is Terrorism?",
			"back": "violent religious group."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": "The primary route of exposure of vesicant agents is the:\n\nA. nervous system.\nB. skin.\nC. vascular system.\nD. respiratory tract.\nSee Chemical Agents",
			"back": "skin."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": "The skin lesions associated with smallpox:\n\nA. are of different shapes and sizes.\nB. are identical in their development.\nC. initially form on the lower trunk.\nD. develop early during the disease.\nSee Biologic Agents",
			"back": "are identical in their development."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": "The type and severity of wounds sustained from incendiary and explosive devices primarily depend on the:\n\nA. type of material used to manufacture the device.\nB. pressure that is generated from the explosion itself.\nC. patient’s distance from the epicenter of the explosion.\nD. size of the structure that was involved in the explosion.\nSee Incendiary and Explosive Devices",
			"back": "patient’s distance from the epicenter of the explosion."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": "The 1996 Summer Olympics bombing is an example of:\n\nA. an ecoterrorist attack.\nB. apocalyptic violence.\nC. state-sponsored terrorism.\nD. domestic terrorism.\nSee Active Shooter Events",
			"back": "domestic terrorism."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": "If the incident command system is already established at the scene of a terrorist attack, the EMT should:\n\nA. locate the medical staging officer to obtain his or her assignment.\nB. begin triaging patients and start treating the most critical ones.\nC. contact the EMS medical director and obtain further instructions.\nD. remain in the rehabilitation area until he or she is assigned a task.\nSee EMT Response to Terrorism",
			"back": "locate the medical staging officer to obtain his or her assignment."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": "Which of the following chemicals is a nerve agent?\n\nA. Phosgene\nB. Soman\nC. Chlorine\nD. Lewisite\nSee Chemical Agents",
			"back": "Soman"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": "Unlike viruses and bacteria, neurotoxins:\n\nA. have a slow onset of symptoms.\nB. cause high fever.\nC. cause skin blistering.\nD. are not contagious.\nSee Biologic Agents",
			"back": "are not contagious."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": "Viral hemorrhagic fevers (VHF), such as Ebola, cause the blood to:\n\nA. attack the bone marrow and destroy cells.\nB. seep out of the blood vessels and tissues.\nC. engorge the brain and cause hemorrhaging.\nD. become thick and spontaneously clot.\nSee Biologic Agents",
			"back": "seep out of the blood vessels and tissues."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": "Cross-contamination occurs when:\n\nA. an EMT is exposed to a victim who has not yet been decontaminated.\nB. an EMT has direct contact with a chemical agent at a terrorist incident.\nC. two EMTs are exposed to the same agent after being decontaminated.\nD. an EMT provides care to a victim after the victim has been decontaminated.\nSee EMT Response to Terrorism",
			"back": "an EMT is exposed to a victim who has not yet been decontaminated."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": "Which of the following statements regarding a “dirty bomb” is correct?\n\nA. The dirty bomb, because of its ability to cause massive damage over a large geographic area, is an effective WMD.\nB. Dirty bombs could injure victims with both radioactive material and the explosive material used to deliver it.\nC. Dirty bombs contain significant amounts of radioactive material and are capable of being delivered via a missile.\nD. The effectiveness of a dirty bomb is solely dependent on the amount of alpha radiation that it emits.\nSee Radiologic/Nuclear Devices",
			"back": "Dirty bombs could injure victims with both radioactive material and the explosive material used to deliver it."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": "A disease vector is defined as:\n\nA. the spectrum of signs that define a disease.\nB. any agent that acts as a carrier or transporter.\nC. the ability of a virus or bacterium to be spread.\nD. the period of time between exposure and illness.\nSee Biologic Agents",
			"back": "any agent that acts as a carrier or transporter."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": "An attack on an abortion clinic would most likely be carried out by a(n):\n\nA. single-issue group.\nB. violent religious group.\nC. extremist political group.\nD. doomsday cult.\nSee What Is Terrorism?",
			"back": "single-issue group."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": "Points of distribution (PODs) are strategically placed facilities where:\n\nA. weapons of mass destruction are distributed.\nB. antidotes, antibiotics, and vaccines are distributed.\nC. chemical weapons are manufactured and distributed.\nD. chemical and biologic weapons are stockpiled.\nSee Biologic Agents",
			"back": "antidotes, antibiotics, and vaccines are distributed."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-41",
		"label": "Chapter 41"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}